good afternoon everybody welcome good to
下午好欢迎大家好
see you as always
看到你一如既往
today we're going to learn about a
今天我们要了解一个
important concept in computer science
在计算机科学中很重要的概念
called virtual memory so consider a
称为虚拟内存，以便考虑
system that uses physical addresses
使用物理地址系统
right we've always our idea about memory
正确的，我们一直 我们对记忆的想法
so far is then that it's a contiguous
到目前为止那么，它是一个 连续的
array of physical physical bytes that we
的物理物理字节阵列， 我们
can access
可以访问
despite by giving some an offset called
尽管给予一定的偏移称为
an address so in a system that uses
一个地址，以便在使用的系统
physical addressing the CPU executes
物理寻址CPU执行
like say a move instruction which
好比说一招指令，
generates an effective address the
产生一个有效地址的
physical address and this address is
物理地址和该 地址
actually the offset of a byte in in main
实际上是一个字节的主偏移
memory so you know here the CPU has
内存让你知道这里的 CPU有
generated a physical address of 4 cents
产生 的4美分 的物理 地址
that address to the to the memory and
该地址给到内存和
then the memory fetches the the word
那么内存取的字
from at that address and then sends it
从该地址，然后发送它
back to the CPU now this is in fact the
回到 CPU 现在这实际上是在
way that very simple microcontrollers
方式很简单的微控制器
work but it's not the way most systems
工作，但它不是像大多数系统
work including your your phones your
工作包括你的手机你
desktops your servers these systems
桌面您的服务器，这些系统
instead virtualized this this main
而不是虚拟化这个这个主
memory now the idea of virtualization is
现在内存虚拟化的思想是
a very important one in computer science
一个很重要的一个计算机科学
and it expands a lot of it applies to a
它扩展了很多它适用于
lot of areas of computer systems now
很多 计算机系统的领域，现在
when you virtualize a resource you you
当您虚拟化的资源你你
present the user of that resource with
呈现资源的与所述用户
some different kind of view of that
一番别样的认为 ，
resource you present typically some kind
资源时通常存在某种
of an abstraction or some kind of a
抽象或某种形式的的
different view of the resource and you
资源和你 的不同看法
do it by interposing on accesses to that
通过插在做访问 到
resource
资源
so in all cases there's some resource
所以在所有的情况下， 有一些资源
and you want to virtualize it and you do
并要虚拟化它，你做
that by intercepting or interposing on
通过截取或插入上
the accesses to that resource okay and
在访问该资源很好，而且
then once you we saw this when we
那么一旦你，我们看到这个时候，我们
created wrapper functions for like
对于像创建包装函数
malloc when I was showing you inter
当我向您展示间的malloc
positioning the same technique is used
定位相同的技术被用于
to virtualize a resource and and once
虚拟化资源，并有一次
you've intercepted that access then you
你拦截的访问，那么你
can deal with it any way you want so
可以对付它，你要等任何一种方式
that's how you have sort of full power
这就是你怎么会有那种充满力量
to change a person to change the view of
改变一个人改变看法
that resource okay so a good example you
该资源 好 了，一个很好的例子 ，你
saw this when we looked at disk and you
看到这个，当我们看着 盘，并
know physically disk consists of
知道物理磁盘组成的
cylinders tracks sectors platters
气瓶跟踪部门拼盘
surfaces and and to access a particular
表面和与访问特定
sector on one of those disks you have to
部门对那些你必须有一个磁盘
specify the cylinder and the track and
指定所述气缸和所述轨道和
the surface okay but we saw that the
表面上不错，但我们看到，
view that this controller is present
查看这个控制器是本
it's actually different it's a
它实际上是不同的这是一个
virtualized view of the disk and the
磁盘和的虚拟化视图
controller instead presents to the
控制器，而不是呈现给
kernel of view of the disk as a series
盘面来看的内核系列
of a sequence of logical blocks and it
逻辑块和它的一个序列的
presents that view by intercepting the
提出这一观点被拦截
requests from the seek from the kernel
从请求从内核 寻求
for i/o and changing those logical block
用于I / O 和改变这些逻辑块
numbers that that that the kernel sends
数字， 该内核发送
into the actual physical address okay so
到 实际的物理地址 好了，
that's a very a very important example
这是一个非常非常重要的例子
of virtualization in a system now the
在系统虚拟化 的 现在
the memory is is a very is a crucial
该内存是一个很是关键
resource in the system and what we found
资源在系统中， 我们发现 了什么
is that it's it's useful to virtualize
是它的虚拟化是非常有用
that that memory resource okay and the
该内存资源 好 和
way this is done remember before we
办法做到这一点 ，我们 还记得 之前
virtualized the disk by having the disk
通过具有磁盘虚拟磁盘
controller intercept request in the case
在的情况下控制器监听请求
of the the main memory resource the
的主 存储器资源
requests are actually intercepted by a
请求由实际截获
piece of hardware called the MMU the
一块硬件 称为 MMU的
memory management unit
内存管理单元
so the way this works is that the CPU
所以这种工作方式是 CPU
executes an instruction say it's a move
执行指令说这是一招
instruction that generates some
指令可生成 一些
effective address so this is actually a
有效的地址，这其实是一个
virtual address
虚拟地址
it's the CPU sends that address to the
它的CPU发送一个地址给
MMU
MMU
which goes through a process called
它经过 这个过程被称为
address translation which will will
地址转换将将就
study later today and it converts that
今天研究后，将其 转换是
virtual address in this case for 1 0 0
在这种 情况下的虚拟地址为1 0 0
into a physical address for which
转换成 物理 地址 ，其为
actually corresponds to the address of
实际上对应的地址
that the data object that we want ok so
数据对象，我们要 确定这样
once once the MMU translates the virtual
一次一次的MMU将虚拟
address to a physical address then the
地址到物理地址， 则
memory will return the the word at that
内存将在返回 的字
at that address
在该地址
so this might wonder why in the world
所以这可能会奇怪，为什么在世界上
would you want to do this well it turns
你想做好这一点事实
out there's all kinds of good reasons to
出有各种各样的好理由
virtualize the the address space and so
虚拟化的地址空间等
before I can explain those to you I let
之前， 我可以解释一下那些你让我
me just define a few a few taught a few
我只是定义了几个几个教了 几
terms so a an address space is a set of
术语所以地址空间是一组
addresses okay so an address spaces is a
解决好了，所以 地址空间 是
set not of not of data bytes but of the
设置不是没有的数据字节，但的
addresses of those bytes and a linear
这些字节和线性的地址
address space is a content is a
地址空间是一个内容 是
contiguous set of contiguous
组连续的连续的
non-negative integers okay so just 0 1 2
非负整数好了，所以只是0 1 2
3 4 5 and so on the virtual address
3 4 5等的虚拟 地址
space is a set of n equal to 2 the N
空间是一组n个等于2的N个
virtual addresses a linear it's a linear
虚拟地址的线性这是一个线性
address space and the physical address
地址空间 和物理 地址
space is a set of m equal to n physical
空间是一组中的m 等于 n物理
addresses ok and so typically the
地址确定，因此通常
deferral address spaces is is usually
延期的地址空间通常是
much larger than the physical address
比物理 地址大得多
space ok the physical address space
空间确定的物理地址空间
corresponds to the amount of DRAM that
对应于 DRAM 的量
you actually have in the system the
你确实有在 系统中
virtual address space is the same for
虚拟地址空间是相同的
all all processes running on that system
该系统上运行的所有的所有进程
okay now why why do we want to implement
现在没事了，为什么，为什么我们要实现
virtual memory why do this why do I do
虚拟内存为什么做这个，为什么我做的
this level of indirection with the MMU
这个级别的间接与MMU
well there's really three big reasons so
也没什么三大原因 使
the first is that virtual memory uses
第一是虚拟存储器使用
the uses the DRAM as a cache for the
在采用DRAM 作为高速缓存
actual data stored on disk okay so you
存储 在磁盘上 的实际数据 好了，所以你
can think of virtual memory as a as a
可以认为虚拟内存的作为
dram cache for data stored on the disk
DRAM高速缓存存储在磁盘上的数据
and this allows us to to use the memory
这允许我们 使用内存
much more efficiently because we only
更高效，因为 我们只
need to cache items that are frequently
需要被频繁缓存项
used right just the same idea that we
正确的使用一样的 想法， 我们
learned when we we talked about caches
据悉，当我们我们谈到缓存
and locality so that's one thing we can
和地方所以这是一两件事，我们 可以
use we can use the memory much more
使用我们可以 使用内存更
efficiently by only using the portions
有效地通过仅使用部分
of the virtual address space by only
仅由虚拟地址空间
actually storing the portions of the
实际存储的部分
virtual address space in the physical
在物理虚拟地址空间
memory okay the second thing is a
内存还好第二件事 是
greatly simplifies memory management so
大大简化了存储管理，
we saw it every process has the same the
我们看到它的每一个进程 都拥有相同的
same view right there's code loaded at
同样的观点在那里代码加载在
code and data are always loaded at the
代码和数据总是被载入在
same address the stack is at the top of
相同的地址 堆栈在顶部
the user visible address space so every
用户可见的地址空间，所以每
process has the same similar-looking
过程具有 相同的 外观类似的
virtual address space but in actual in
虚拟地址空间 ，但在实际中
actuality that the the memory that
现实是，在 内存
corresponds to those those addresses is
对应于那些那些地址被
actually scattered all over main memory
实际上分散在主存
okay so so that's a really important
好了，所以这是一个非常重要的
important center set of virtual memory
重要的中心设置 虚拟内存
and then finally it allows us to protect
然后最后它 使我们 能够保护
accesses so remember we had to a process
存取所以记得我们有一个过程
we saw that a process provides the
我们看到的是一个过程提供
separate address space that that's
独立的地址空间是这
protected from accesses by other
其他保护访问
processes
流程
okay so virtual memory allows us to
好了，所以虚拟内存可以让我们
create these these separate protected
创建这些这些 单独的保护
private address spaces okay
私有地址空间好吗
and so what we'll do today we'll look in
而我们今天会做所以我们将看看在
more detail at these three ideas and
在这三个理念更多的细节和
then we'll and then we'll go into the
然后我们会，然后我们会进入
specifics of address translation so I'm
地址转换的细节，所以我
going to for the first the first part of
要为第一的第一部分
this lecture we're going to talk about
本次讲座我们要谈
address translation just in kind of
只是那种地址转换
high-level terms but then we'll go into
高层次的条件，但随后我们将进入
the details at the end you can see how
在最后 的细节 ，你可以看到
it how it really works okay so let's
它是如何真的工作好让 我们
look at VM as a tool for caching so
看看VM作为高速缓存的工具，所以
conceptually you can think of the your
概念上，你能想到的你
virtual memory as a sequence of bytes
虚拟存储器作为字节序列
stored on disk okay and then the
存储在磁盘上没关系，然后
contents of that of the the contents of
那中的内容内容
that virtual memory stored on disk are
存储在磁盘上虚拟内存是
cached in DRAM okay so think of the the
在DRAM缓存好了，所以想到的
DRAM is a cache for this this array of
DRAM 是此这个阵列的高速缓冲存储器
contiguous bytes stored on the disk and
存储在盘上 连续 的字节 和
just like any cache the the data is
就像任何高速缓存中的数据是
broken up into blocks okay and then we
分解成块 行不行 ，然后我们
have so here we have the and those
有那么这里 我们有那些
blocks for virtual memory systems are
用于虚拟存储器系统块是
called pages they're typically typically
所谓网页他们通常一般
larger than much larger than the cache
比大于高速缓存大得多大
blocks that we that we study done so for
我们认为我们的研究做了这么块
K bytes typically instead of the 64
千字节，而不是通常的64个
bytes like that we that we learned about
字节喜欢我们，我们了解了
in when we studied cache memories so
在我们研究的高速缓冲存储器，所以
this virtual memory conceptually you can
这个虚拟内存概念，你可以
think of it as being a sequence of pages
把它看作是页面序列
stored on the disk so called virtual
存储所谓的虚拟磁盘上
pages and each of these pages will
页面和这些页面会
identify with a number so here's virtual
与一些识别所以这里的虚拟
page zero virtual page one and then a
第零 虚拟页面之一，然后一
subset of those pages are stored in in
这些页面的子集存储在
the physical memory in the physical DRAM
在物理DRAM的物理存储器
memory and then there's some mapping
内存中，然后有一些映射
function that tells us which pages have
函数，告诉我们有哪些网页
been cached okay so in this case I've
在这种情况下， 我已经缓存好了，
just shown a snapshot where we have
只是显示一个快照，我们有
three virtual pages cached somewhere in
三个虚拟缓存的页面某处
DRAM okay and there there's no relation
DRAM 没关系，有没有关系
between the virtual page number and the
虚拟页码和之间
physical page number that it's mapped to
，它的映射到物理页号
some of these pages
一些网页
are not cached so they're at they're
不缓存 ，因此 他们在他们
still stored on disk so in this case VP
仍然存储在磁盘上，以便在这种情况下VP
2 is still stored on disk and there's
2仍然存储在磁盘上并有
some pages which aren't even allocated
它甚至不分配一些网页
so they're they don't exist on the disk
所以他们不 磁盘上存在
yet it's a way to think of that right
但它认为该权利的方式
because we really wouldn't want to store
因为 我们真的不希望 存储
every single page in address space with
每一个单页的地址空间
that's to the size to the 48 we really
这是对大小为48， 我们真的
wouldn't want to store all those those
不想存储所有的这些
on disk so most of the address space is
在磁盘上所以大部分的地址空间是
unallocated ok so we can just think of
未分配的确定，所以我们可以试想的
this so this this DRAM is just a cache
这使该DRAM这仅仅是一个高速缓存
but it has a much different organization
但它有很多不同的组织
than the cache memories we studied
比高速缓冲存储器我们研究
earlier and these the difference is
更早这些差别
driven by that the enormous miss penalty
通过巨大的命中判罚驱动
when you go from if you have a cache and
当你从如果你有一个缓存去
DRAM the the Miss penalty would to such
DRAM 的小姐处罚会这样
a data item from the disk is huge we so
从磁盘中的数据项是巨大的，我们这么
the design of this virtual memory cache
这个虚拟内存缓存设计
is totally driven by this enormous miss
完全被这个巨大的推动小姐
penalty and so as a result that blocks
罚分和所以作为结果的块
are larger so remember we talked about
较大所以记得我们谈到了
that the block size is kind of a
该块尺寸是 种一
trade-off between sort of useful getting
排序的有用之间权衡获得
used being able to usefully amortize the
使用能有效地分摊
cost of fetching that block versus sort
取的成本，阻止与排序
of consuming too much of this scarce
中消耗了太多这种稀缺的
cache space right so in this case our
缓存空间 权所以在这种 情况下，我们
cache memories were 64 byte blocks
高速缓冲存储器，分别为64字节的块
virtual most virtual memory systems has
虚拟大多数虚拟内存系统具有
like 4 K byte blocks with and with an
像，并用4个KB字节的块
option to increase to 4 megabytes in the
选项来增加在4兆字节
case of x86 and now this cash and other
86的情况下，现在这个现金及其他
consequence of the enormous miss penalty
巨大的缺失损失的后果
is that you really want to have as large
是，你真的想有大
associativity as you can remember we saw
关联你能记住我们看到
with direct mapped cache is that were
与直接映射缓存是为
subject to to these conflict misses and
受 这些冲突未和
and if you if you increase the
如果你，如果你增加
associativity of the cache you reduce
您减少缓存的关联性
the the probability of those conflict
这些冲突的概率
misses but you never completely
未命中但你永远不完全
eliminate them until you have a fully so
消灭他们，直到你有一个完全如此
I should've cash with just one set okay
我应该 现金只用一套好吗
so in a virtual memory in a virtual
所以在虚拟存储器中的虚拟
memory cache it's fully associative
内存缓存 是完全关联
there's one set and each virtual page
有一组和每个虚拟页面
can go anywhere in the cache okay so
可以在高速缓存中去任何地方好了，
this requires a really complicated
这需要一个非常复杂的
mapping function somehow we're going to
映射功能在某种程度上 ， 我们要
keep track of where all these cached
跟踪所有这些缓存
pages are and we can't really do a
页面，我们真的不能做
search that would be that would be way
搜索，这将是这将是这样
too inexpensive so you remember when we
太便宜的，所以你还记得我们
with a cache memory the hardware
与高速缓冲存储器硬件
actually did a search within the set a
实际上做了 一个 集内搜索
parallel search to to find try to find a
并行搜索 来 找到试图找到
cache line but with a software cache
高速缓存行，但与软件缓存
like this that that's not feasible
像这样的，这不是可行
all right so somehow we're going to have
没事所以在某种程度上我们将 有
to remember where these cache blocks are
要记住，这些缓存块
in this very large set and again because
在这个非常大集，并再次 因为
it's so expensive if you make a mistake
它是如此昂贵，如果你犯了一个 错误
when you're trying to identify a run
当你试图找出 运行
victim victim page if you make a mistake
受害者的受害者页面，如果你犯了一个错误
and you evict a page that then is
你驱逐一个页面，然后是
referenced again in the near future you
在不久的将来再次引用您
pay a big price for it okay
付出大代价 好吗
so virtual memory caches have much more
所以虚拟内存高速缓存有更
sophisticated replacement algorithms
复杂的替换算法
than like simple LRU that we saw with
不是像我们看到用简单的LRU
cache memories now they're these
高速缓冲存储器，现在他们这些
replacement algorithms are outside of
替换算法是外
the scope of this course you'll learn
本课程您将 学习 范围
about them when you take os but because
关于他们，当你把 操作系统，但因为
it's in software we can we can afford to
它在软件，我们 可以，我们能负担得起
do very expensive replacement algorithms
做的非常昂贵的 替换算法
and we can take a long fairly relatively
我们需要很长的还算比较
long time to execute the code for those
很长一段时间来执行代码的 那些
algorithms because any time we spend
算法，因为任何时候我们花
figuring out a victim block will be much
找出受害者块将大大
less than the the cost of making a
不到 制作的成本
mistake and paying the the access time
错误和支付的访问时间
then this time the miss penalty to to
那么这一次的 错过 点球 ，以
disk and then also as a result of
磁盘， 然后也可 作为结果
virtual memory systems never use right
虚拟内存系统从未使用权
through just because it takes to one
通过只是 因为它需要 一个
like so they always use right back and
像这样他们总是用右后卫和
they try to defer writing anything back
他们试图推迟写任何东西
to the disk as long as possible
磁盘尽可能长
all right now how do we keep track
现在好了，我们如何跟踪
somehow we have to keep track of this
不知何故，我们必须跟踪这个
complicated cache and DRAM and the data
复杂的缓存和DRAM 及 数据
structure that keeps track of the
结构， 保持轨道
location of the virtual pages in in
在虚拟页面 的位置
memory is called the page table now a
现在的内存被称为页表
page table is just a data structure in
页表只是 在数据结构
memory that the kernel maintains for as
内存内核维护用于为
part of each process context okay so
每个进程上下文的一部分好了，所以
every process has its own page table and
每个进程都有自己的页表 和
it's just a it's an array of so called
它只是一个 它是 所谓 的数组
page table entries or PT es where PT ek
页表项或PT ES其中PT EK
contains the physical address of
包含的物理地址
physical page K in D Ram okay so here's
D中拉姆物理页。K 好吧所以这里的
how it works there's there's this page
它是如何工作有有此页
table in DRAM there's virtual pages
表DRAM有虚拟页面
stored on disk
存储在磁盘上
and then there's their stuff and then
然后有自己的东西 ，然后
there's physical there's virtual pages
有身体有虚拟页
stored in various physical pages in DRAM
存储在DRAM各种物理页
and then the page table keeps track of
然后页表跟踪
where those are stored so here we have a
其中那些存储所以在这里我们有一个
case this PT e 1 corresponds to virtual
情况下， 这 PTë1对应于虚拟
page 1 and in this case it says that
第1页，在这种情况下，它说，
virtual page 1 is mapped into physical
虚拟页面1被映射到物理
page 0 virtual page 2 is mapped into
第0页虚拟页2被映射到
physical page 1 and so on now some of
物理页1和 现在 这样 的一些
these the pages that aren't in memory
这些不在内存的页面
are stored on disk the allocated pages
存储在磁盘上的分配页
and so for those pages the page table
所以对这些页面 的页表
entry contains a pointer to the location
条目包含的指针位置
of that that page on disk so think of it
那对磁盘页面，以便把它
as a logical block number where that
作为逻辑块数，其中该
page can be found on the disk and then
页面可以在磁盘上，然后找到
some of the pages are not allocated so
一些网页都没有这么分配
there's there's a no a null entry in the
有有一个没有空条目的
page table now a page hit so this is
页表打到现在一个页面，所以这是
just a cache right so we have hits and
只是缓存权，所以我们有命中和
misses so a page yet occurs when there's
错过这样一个页面时有发生尚
a reference to a word invert in the
在一个字反相的参考
virtual address space that's contained
多数民众赞成包含的虚拟地址空间
in a page that's cached in the DRAM ok
该公司在DRAM缓存 确定 一个页面
so let's say that we have you know the
所以我们说，我们有你知道
CPU execute this and move instruction it
CPU 执行这一点，移动 指令它
generates a virtual address the MMU
生成一个虚拟地址的MMU
looks up in the page table and let's say
在页表中查找并让我们说
this virtual address is somewhere within
这个虚拟地址内的某处
virtual page 2 ok so that the MMU
虚拟第 2 页 确定，这样的MMU
looks up the page table entry number 2
查找的页表项数2
and it fought it extracts the physical
和它打它提取物理
address of that of that virtual page 2
那虚拟页面2的地址
ok so that's a hit so in this case in
好了 ，所以这是一个命中 因此，在这种情况下，
this case the
这种情况下，
the page is in memory it's cached in
该页面是在 内存 中 它的缓存中
memory and so we have a hit-and and now
记忆， 所以我们有一个 打了，现在
the the memory can can return that can
该内存可以可以返回，可
return that physical address to the MMU
返回物理地址的MMU
okay now a miss is a reference to a word
现在没事了 一个 小姐是 一个字 一个参考
that's not cached in in in physical
这不是在缓存中的物理
memory so in this case virtual page 0 1
存储器中，从而在这种情况下虚拟页0 1
2 3 is not cached in DRAM it's stored
2 3 没有在DRAM缓存 它的存储
it's stored on the disk so now that
它使现在，这是存储在磁盘上
triggers a an exception ok page fault
触发异常确定页面错误
exception in the hardware the hardware
除了在硬件硬件
triggers the exception and that causes
引发异常，并导致
the transfer of control to a hunk of
控制 转移 到的大块
code in the kernel called the page fault
在内核代码中调用的页面错误
handler which then selects a victim to
处理程序，其然后选择一个牺牲品
be evicted in this case virtual page 4
在这种情况下， 虚拟第 4 页被驱逐
and it fetches virtual page 3 from the
并从获取虚拟页3
disk loads it up into memory and if and
磁盘加载它到内存中， 如果和
then changes and and then updates this
然后改变和再更新 此
page table entry to reflect the fact
页表项，以反映这一事实
that virtual page 4 is now stored on
虚拟第4页现在存储在
disk and if virtual page 4 had been
磁盘，并在虚拟页4已经
modified at any time it would have to
在任何时候，将不得不 修改
write the contents of it
写它的内容
that's a disk as well so once the once
这是一个磁盘，以及因此一旦一次
the handler is copied virtual page 3
处理程序被复制虚拟页3
into memory the instruction that caused
到存储器中导致该指令
the page fault now can be re executed ok
页面错误，现在可以重新确定执行
so once the so when the page fault
所以一旦所以当页面错误
handler and the kernel returns it
处理程序和内核返回它
returns to the faulting instruction
返回到错误指令
which then reacts Acutes and now that
然后反应Acutes 和现在
pages when the MMU checks that the Pte
当MMU检查该网页的私人
corresponding to that page it finds that
对应于该网页时发现，
it's indeed cache so so now the
它现在是确实缓存，以便使
instruction can continue and we can
指令可以继续，我们可以
fetch that
获取该
whatever whatever word at that virtual
在虚拟无论什么字
address from from the DRAM okay now we
从DRAM还好现在我们解决
can we can allocate a new page of memory
我们可以分配一个新的 内存 页
so in this example virtual page 0 1 2 3
所以在这个例子 虚拟页0 1 2 3
4 5 is not allocated so if you need to
4 5不分配，所以如果你需要
let's say you do malloc of a very large
假设你做的一个非常大的malloc
chunk of virtual address space if it's
虚拟地址空间的块，如果它是
those pages if one of those pages hasn't
这些页面如果 这些页面 中的一个 也没有
been allocated yet then the kernel
被分配又那么内核
actually or the malloc function actually
实际上或malloc函数 实际上
has to create allocate that memory by
必须通过创建分配内存
calling a function called s break ok and
调用叫 分手吧 OK功能和
then what s break does is actually
那么什么分手吧不实际
allocates this this page and records
此分配这个页面和记录
where it's loaded now would probably
它现在加载大概会
actually put it up into now I guess it
居然把它变成现在我猜
would it wouldn't actually show up in
会不会真正出现在
that in the DRAM cache until it was that
，在DRAM缓存中，直到它是
page was touched
页面被感动
okay so just allocating space just
好了，只是分配空间只
changes this page table entry and then
改变了这一页表项，然后
when that page is actually touched then
当页面被实际触摸然后
it'll be brought into the cache so I
它会被带入高速缓存，所以我
don't know about you but the first time
不知道你，但第 一次
I learned about this I was I was pretty
我得知这个情况我是我是 相当
appalled it just seemed like the most
震惊它只是似乎是最
inefficient terrible idea right how in
权如何在效率低下的可怕的想法
the world can you afford to on every
世界你能负担得起每
single every single instruction that
单每一个指令
uses memory do all this copying back and
使用内存做这一切的拷贝回来，
forth and looking up in tables and it
提出并以表和它仰视
just seems like an awful idea
似乎只是一个可怕的想法
but once again locality saves us ok and
但再次局部性拯救我们确定，
it it actually works because programs
它它的实际工作，因为方案
have locality ok and it's actually
有局部性确定，它实际上是
fairly efficient and the reason is that
相当有效，其原因在于
at any point of time programs tend to
在时间程序的任何点往往
access a set of pages called the working
访问一组页面称为工作
set ok just by locality right by by
设置OK只是局部性权由
temporal locality by the principle of
时间局部性的原则
temporal locality and spatial locality
时间局部性和空间局部性
you tend to sort of reuse the same
你会 有点重复使用相同的
things reuse nearby things ok
事情重用 OK 附近的东西
and so if that working set is less than
所以如果工作集小于
the main memory size then all of the
主存储器大小，那么所有的
pages in the current working set will
在当前的工作集的页面将
fit in memory and then things will be
适合在内存中，然后事情会
great okay but if the some of the
伟大的不错，但如果一些
working set sizes for every process
工作集大小每个进程
right our systems running multiple
就在我们 的系统上运行多个
processes if it exceeds the main memory
如果它超过 主存储器处理
size then you have this this meltdown
大小，然后你有这个这个 危机
where processes are thrashing each other
其中处理颠簸彼此
and causing pages to be copied back and
而导致网页被复制回
forth so you never ever know process
第四，所以你永远不会知道过程
ever gets its working set fully into
曾经被 其工作设置 完全进入
into memory okay and we'll look at a
到内存没关系，我们来看看一个
technique when we look at address
当我们看地址技术
translation we'll look at a little
翻译我们来看看一点点
hardware cache called a translation
硬件高速缓存称为翻译
lookaside buffer that that further
后备缓冲器进一步
exploits the locality property of
利用的局部性
programs okay so that's virtual memory
好规划，使虚拟内存
is a tool for caching it's also a member
是 其高速缓存 工具 也是一个成员
to Oh for memory management and it
哦对内存管理 和IT
greatly simplifies all kinds of aspects
大大简化了各种方面的
of memory management for the kernel so
内存管理 为核心 的 这样
the key idea is that each process has
其核心思想是，每个进程都有
its own virtual address space the kernel
自己的虚拟地址空间内核
the kernel implements this bite by
内核实现此 咬伤
giving each process its own separate
给每个进程自己单独
page table in the context of that
在 该 背景下 页表
process so it's just a data structure in
过程所以它只是一个数据结构
the kernel that the process key that the
内核的过程中的关键是，
criminal keeps for that process and the
刑事保持该进程和
the page table for each process Maps the
每个进程的页表的映射
virtual address space for that process
该进程的虚拟地址空间
now what's interesting so you have that
现在是什么让你有真有意思
these these pages contiguous pages in
这些这些页的连续页
the virtual address space can be mapped
虚拟地址空间 可以被映射
anywhere in the in the in the DRAM in
任何地方的在DRAM中
the physical address space so and they
物理地址空间 ，所以 ，他们
can be scattered all over the place and
可分散各地的 地方 ，
different virtual pages and different
不同的虚拟 页面和不同
processes can be mapped to different
过程可以被映射到 不同
physical pages so here we have virtual
物理页面所以在这里，我们有虚拟
page one which is mapped to physical
被映射到物理页面一个
page two in process one but in process
第二页中的过程之一，但在过程中
two virtual page one is mapped to
两个虚拟页面一个被映射到
physical page eight okay so in this way
物理Page显效8 好了，所以用这种方式
we can
我们可以
scent of you two to each to to the
你的气味两 到各 向
programmer and to the tools that each
程序员和工具 ，每个
process has a very similar address space
过程中有 一个非常相似的地址空间
virtual address space same size address
虚拟地址空间大小相同地址
space code and data start at the same
空间的代码和数据开始于相同
place but then the actual pages that
地方 ，但那么实际 的页面
that process used can be scattered in
使用该过程可以将分散在
memory ok and then it gives us the most
内存确定，然后它给了 我们最
efficient way to use the memory if we
如果使用内存有效的方式，我们
didn't have this mechanism think about
没有这个机制思考
how would you keep track let's say you
你将如何跟踪假设您
had 50 processes running on the machine
已经在机器上运行50个进程
at any point in time how in the world
在 时间 如何在世界上 的任何一点
would you keep track of where all of the
你会跟踪 所有 的 的
data those processes were using well one
数据的那些过程进行了使用公一个
technique that you could imagine in fact
技术， 你可以在事实上想象
it was used in the in the bad old days
它是在用在坏 日子
the for virtual memory one thing you can
将 虚拟内存一件事你可以
imagine is that just give every process
可以想象的是，只给每个进程
its own chunk of the physical address
其自身的物理地址块
space just take your physical address
空间 只是把你的物理地址
space partition it and then each process
空间划分它，然后将每个处理
gets loads and runs and it's its own
得到加载和运行， 它是它自己
part of the address space well this has
地址空间 的一部分， 以及该有
all kinds of problems right I mean you
各种问题好吧， 我的意思是你
could if you what do you do if you add a
可如果你什么你，如果你添加一个做
process so you really can't partition
过程所以你真的不能分区
the address space you really have to
你真的 要地址空间
sort of say well each process get some
那种说好每道工序得到一些
little chunk and I'm going to reserve
小块，我要去 准备金
some of the address space in case
在一些情况下 ，地址空间
there's new processes that need memory
有需要 的内存 新工艺
another problem is that now you have to
另一个问题是， 现在你必须
write your programs
编写程序
you can't just blink your program ahead
你不能只是眨眼程序提前
of time because it has to be relocated
的时间，因为它必须被重新定位
when it's loaded right because you don't
当它的加载 正确的，因为你 不知道
you know a process you don't know where
你知道一个过程中，你 不知道在哪里
in the memory it's going to go it's
在存储它会去它的
going to get some chunk so you have to
会 所以你必须 得到一些大块
either relocate all the the references
要么重新定位的所有引用
the references to global symbols at when
在何时全局符号引用
it's actually loaded or you have to
它的实际加载 或你必须
create a system where all of the
创建一个系统 ，所有 的
instructions are relative so there's
指令是相对所以有
there's no absolute addresses all
没有绝对地址的所有
addresses are relative to say the start
地址是相对的说法开始
of the program something like that so
方案 类似 的东西 ，所以
anyway all of these things are just
反正所有 的这些东西都只是
terribly complicated and they're all
非常复杂，他们都
solved beautifully by virtual memory
通过虚拟存储解决精美
so the each virtual page can be mapped
因此每个虚拟页可以映射
to any physical page so that really
任何物理页面，以便 真正
helps simplify things and even at
有助于简化的东西 ，甚至在
different times the same virtual page
不同时间对同一虚拟页面
can be stored at in different physical
可被存储 在不同的 物理
pages at different times right so if a
在不同的时间 正确 的网页 ，所以如果一个
page for it for a while it might be
它页了，虽然可能
cached in one physical page then it gets
缓存在一个物理页面，然后它会
swapped out and the next time it's
换出， 下一次，它是
referenced it can get cached in a
引用它可以获取缓存在
different physical page is that if it's
不同的物理页面是 ， 如果它的
no longer available right so it provides
不再可用 右 所以它提供
sort of the most flexible scheduling
排序最灵活的调度
freedom in the way that we in the way
自由 的方式，我们在路上
that we manage the memory and it also
我们管理内存，它也
provides this really neat capability
提供这种 非常灵巧的能力
where you can map virtual pages to the
在这里你可以映射虚拟页到
same physical page so there's this is a
相同的物理页面 ，以便有，这是一个
very simple straightforward way for
对于非常简单直接的方法
multiple processes to share certain code
多个进程共享某些代码
or data ok and what what you do is you
或数据确定， 你 做 的 是你
just the page table entry in these
只是 在这些 页表项
different processes just points to the
不同的进程刚刚指向
same physical page so in this case
相同的物理页面所以在这种情况下，
virtual page 2 points to physical page 6
虚拟页2分至6的物理页
in each of in each of the page tables
每个在每个页表
for process 1 and process 2 so this is
过程1和过程2，所以这是
how shared libraries are implemented
如何共享库实现
right so Lib C is the same code for
右所以 库C 是相同的代码
every process running on the system so
在系统上 运行的每个过程 ，以便
lips nee just needs to be loaded once
嘴唇娘家只需要加载一次
into physical into physical memory and
成物理到物理存储器和
then processes that want to access
那么想的进程访问
functions and data in Lib C just map the
功能和数据在库Ç只是 映射
pages in their virtual address space to
在他们的虚拟地址空间 的页面
the physical pages where it sees
在那里 看到 的物理 页面
actually loaded ok so now there's only
实际负载的确定，所以现在有只
one copy of let's see everywhere in the
让我们来看看无处不在 的的一个副本
system but every process thinks it's got
系统但是每个进程认为这是有
its own copy
自己的副本
now this this virtual memory for met
现在遇到了这个这个虚拟内存
using virtual memory to help simplify
使用虚拟内存来帮助简化
memory management greatly simplifies
内存管理大大简化
linking and loading ok for the reasons I
链接和加载确定的原因，我
mentioned before linkers now can assume
现在的接头前面提到可以假设
that every every program is going to be
每一个每一个 节目将是
loaded at exactly the same place so the
加载在完全相同的地方，以便在
linker knows ahead of time where
链接器知道的时间，其中提前
everything is going to be and then it
一切都将是，然后
can resolve it can relocate all those
可以解决这个问题可以重新定位所有
references accordingly now it really
因此现在引用它真的
makes loading as simple so what
使得加载简单等什么
so exactly the loader if you want to
所以完全加载器 ，如果你想
load a program now eggs xee looks at the
现在加载程序 鸡蛋XEE 着眼于
elf binary the executable binary ok
ELF二进制可执行二进制 OK
it sees how it identifies how big the
它认为它是如何确定多大
code and the data sections in that
在该代码和数据 部分
binary are it allocates virtual memory
二进制是它分配的虚拟存储器
starting at a fixed address for the code
开始在一个固定地址的代码
and data see it creates pts for them and
和数据看到为他们创造点和
marks each of them is invalid ok so each
标志着他们每个人是无效的确定，所以每个
each Pte contains a valid mapping so
每个私人包含一个有效的映射 ，以便
each Pte
每个私人
that's mapped to code and data contains
这被映射到代码和数据包含
a valid physical page number but then
有效的物理页面数量，但随后
the it does this trick of setting the
将它设置的这一招
valid bit to zero so when the when the
有效位为零 ， 所以当时
MMU x encounters the Pte whose valid bit
MMU X遇到其有效位的私人
is 0 it triggers a page fault right it
0它触发页面错误 正确的IT
looks as though that page is not has not
看起来好像那个页面是不是还没有
been initialized yet so it's kind of a
尚未初始化， 所以这类型的
trick right and then that triggers a
诱骗右侧，然后触发 一个
page fault to the kernel and then the
页错误的内核，然后
kernel
核心
till then can then copy that that page
那么到那时可以复制该页面
into into the physical memory ok so this
进入到物理内存 确定，所以这
the the loading actually programs and
在装载实际的方案和
data aren't actually they're not load
数据实际上并没有他们没有 加载
loaded you know they're not just like
加载，可以知道他们是不一样
copied into memory it happens as a
复制到存储器中它发生作为
result of
结果
of page fault it happens as a result of
缺页的正好作为的 结果
misses when and it's deferred to until a
当与它推迟到直到错过
bite in that page is accessed okay so
咬在页面被访问好了，
this is called demand paging okay but
这就是所谓的按需分页不错，但
it's really just like any any of the
它真的就像 任何任何
other caches we've looked at right you
我们已经看了对你的其他缓存
don't you don't load a block into the
难道你不块装入
cache until a word within that block is
缓存中，直到 该块 内的字
accessed okay so so loading actually so
访问好了，所以实际上加载等等
loading is actually this is a very
加载其实这是一个 很
efficient mechanism right because you
有效的机制正确的，因为你
may have a program that contains a huge
可能有 一个 蕴含着巨大 的程序
say a huge array a large array but
说一个巨大的数组大阵，但
you're only accessing a portion of that
你只能访问的那一部分
array so that that entire array won't
阵列，以使得整个阵列不会
actually be be allocated the pages will
实际上分配的页面会
only come into DRAM when they're when a
只有进入 DRAM时，他们当
word within that page is touched so if
该页面中的文字被触摸，所以如果
you're only accessing a portion of this
你只访问其中的一部分
extremely large array only the data that
非常大的阵列仅 数据
you access gets gets loaded and used so
您访问被被加载并使用，因此
it's a it's a very very smart mechanism
这是一个它是一个非常非常聪明的机制
and extremely helpful for for allowing
并允许非常有帮助
us to use this precious memory resource
我们利用 这个宝贵的内存资源
okay so the third the third motivation
好了，所以第三第三动机
for virtual memory is that it helps us
虚拟内存 ，它 可以帮助我们
protect portions of memory so you recall
保护的内存部分，所以你还记得
that our processes
我们的流程
you know portions of our virtual address
你知道我们的虚拟地址的部分
space or read-only like the the code
空间或只读 类的代码
section okay and there are other
部分很好，而且还有 其他
portions of the address space that can
地址空间 的部分 ， 可以
only be executed by the kernel okay so
仅由内核好了，所以执行
on on systems like x86 64
关于像86 64系统
it's a 64-bit system so the pointers and
这是一个64位 系统， 使指针 和
addresses are 64 bits but in actuality
地址是64位，但 在实际中
the real virtual address space is 48
真实虚拟地址空间是48
bits okay so it's only its to the 48 and
位好吧，这只是 其对48和
then the the high-order bits after bit
然后比特后的高位比特
48 are either all zeros
48要么全零
are all ones okay so and that's so
全部为一 好了，那是如此
that's just the that's the that sort of
这仅仅是 这就是那种
Intel's rule okay for and so the the
英特尔的统治好 并因此在
addresses where the high order bits are
其中高位比特是地址
all ones are reserved for the colonel
所有的人都保留给 上校
the Colonel's code and the Colonel's
上校的代码和上校
data okay the addresses were all the
数据还行 地址均在
bits are zero reserved for user code
位零保留用于用户代码
okay so so any reference any address
好了，所以任何引用任何地址
that contains all ones and those high
它包含了所有的人与那些高
order bits is by definition either code
阶位是由定义或者代码
or data in the kernel and so you can you
或者在 内核 和 数据 ，因此你可以在你
can add bits to the Pte that specify
可以位添加到 私人 指定
whether certain virtual pages can be
某些虚拟页面是否可以
accessed by user code or if they have to
用户代码或者，如果他们要访问
be accessed by the by the kernel so
内核因此受到访问
so-called supervisor mode and you can
所谓的监督模式中，你可以
also add bits that control whether that
还要补充一点控制是否该位
that page can be read written or
可以读取页的书面或
executed okay so this this executes bit
执行好所以这此位执行
is new with x86 64 it didn't exist in
是新的x86 64它没有存在
32-bit x86 systems and this is that this
32位x86系统 ，这 是这
is the this is the technique that's used
是这是所使用的技术
now to try to prevent against attack lab
现在就来试试， 防止对攻击实验室
code injection style attacks because it
代码注入式攻击，因为它
makes it impossible if this bit is set
使得它不可能，如果此位被设置
you can't load instructions from from
你不能从加载指令
any anybody within that page and so in
该网页，所以在内的任何人
fact it was it was this the introduction
事实上， 它是这个介绍
of this execute that that sir led to
这是执行爵士就是导致
things like return-oriented programming
之类的东西返回导向编程
attacks like you did in your attack lab
像你这样的攻击在你的攻击实验室做
okay so this by just the simple
好了，所以这仅通过简单的
technique of adding adding bits to the
添加添加比特到的技术
Pte we provide a way an automatic way to
PTE我们提供一个方式自动方式
to protect different parts of our
保护的不同部分我们
virtual address space from unauthorized
未经授权的虚拟地址空间
access accesses and then the MMU
访问 通道，然后MMU
actually checks these bits on each
实际上检查每个这些位
access and if there's if there's a
访问，如果有，如果有一个
problem you know if if you're trying to
问题你知道，如果你想
do a right and the right the right
做一个正确和权
that's not enabled then it throws an
这不是启用，则它 抛出一个
exception which then the kernel the
例外然后内核
kernel
核心
deals with okay so so far I've been
用好交易所以到目前为止， 我一直
talking about address translation and
谈论地址转换 和
kind of high-level high-level terms so
一种高层次高水平的条款，以便
let's let's get down to details and see
让我们，让我们坐下来详细看
how it really works
它是如何真正起作用
okay so we're given a virtual address of
好了，所以我们给出的虚拟地址
n elements physical address of M
n个元素M的物理地址
elements like I said before n is usually
像I族元素，所述前 n通常是
larger than M but it doesn't have to be
大于M的，但它并没有被
okay it's perfectly there's no reason m
还好这是完全没有理由米
m could be much larger than N and
米能比N和大得多的
there's there it's typically not but but
有没有这通常 不是但却
it could be and so given these to adjust
它可以因此考虑到 这些调整
spaces we have a map function that takes
空间，我们有一个映射函数，它
that maps from V to P with an optional
即从 V 映射 至 P与可选
empty set or with an additional empty
空集或者与另外的空
set and so for virtual address a map a
虚拟地址映射一个集等
is equal to a prime if the data at
等于黄金如果数据在
virtual address a is its physical
虚拟地址是其物理
address a prime okay so I mean that's
解决的首要好了，所以我的意思是 这
just what we've it's just a little more
正是我们就把它更只是一个 小
formal way to say well we've been
正规的方式说好了，我们已经
talking about before with our diagrams
前谈论我们的图
and then map a is the empty set if the
然后映射一个是空集，如果
data at virtual address a is not in
在虚拟地址的数据不在
physical memory okay so just for a
物理内存 所以 只是 一个 好吗
summary I'm going to put up a list of
总之我要去忍受的列表
all the symbols we're going to be using
我们将所有的符号被 使用
an address translation but this is just
地址翻译，但是这仅仅是
for some way this is just for reference
一些方法，这只是参考
if you're using the slides later on okay
如果你以后使用上 好的幻灯片
so here's how address translation where
所以这里的如何地址转换哪里
the page table works so we're given some
页表的作品所以我们给出了一些
virtual address that consists of n bits
一个由n位的虚拟地址
and we have blocks that consist of whose
我们有一个由它的块
size can be represented with P bits okay
尺寸可以用 好P位 来表示
so think about this now thee so this is
所以想想这个，现在 你 这样，这是
very similar to what we looked at when
非常类似于我们看的时候
we did caching you know the address bits
我们没有缓存你知道地址位
for a cache so these first P bits
用于高速缓存等等这些第一P位
correspond to the page offset so this is
对应页偏移，所以这是
analogous to the blocks offsets that we
类似于块偏移，我们
saw with caches and then the remaining
与高速缓存看到，然后剩下的
bits correspond to the the virtual page
位对应于虚拟页
number this is remember this is fully
数这 是 记住这 是完全
associative right so there's only one
联想右所以，只有一个
set so in a fully associative cache
在全关联缓存设置成
everything after the block offset is
一切后，块偏移
tagged so think of this as like a tag
标记所以认为 这 就像一个标签
this is the this is what uniquely
这是 ，这是唯一什么
identifies this block and we in virtual
识别该块和我们在虚拟
memory parlance we refer to it as a
内存的说法，我们把它 称为一个
virtual page number now the page table
现在虚拟页码的页表
the beginning of the page table is
页表的开头是
pointed to by this page table based
基于 此 页表指出，
register on intel systems that's it's
在 Intel系统 上注册 ，就是这样的
called cr3 control register 3 but this
所谓的CR3 控制寄存器3但这
register this register contains the
注册这个寄存器包含
physical address of the page table in
在页表 的物理地址
memory ok
内存OK
the beginning of that and so when the
那开始，所以当
when the CPU presents a virtual page a
当CPU呈现虚拟页面
virtual address to the MMU it takes the
虚拟地址到MMU所花费的
virtual page number and uses that as an
虚拟页码和使用， 作为一个
index into the page table and then it
索引页表，然后将其
and then it int and that identifies a
然后将其 int和标识
page table entry which contains if this
其中包含如果此页表项
is mapped into memory it contains the
被映射到存储器中所包含的
physical address of the of the
的物理地址
corresponding physical page okay so the
对应的物理页 还好使
whole purpose of address translation is
地址转换的全部目的就是
to come up you're given a virtual
拿出 你给一个 虚拟
address and you want to come up with a
地址，并希望拿出一个
corresponding physical address ok so the
对应的物理地址确定，因此
physical address the physical the
物理地址的物理
physical page number portion of the
的物理页号部分
physical address comes out of the page
物理地址出来的页面
table entry and this is interesting the
表项，这很 有趣的
the physical page offset portion of the
物理页偏移的所述部分
physical address comes out of the
物理地址出来的
virtual page offset and if those bits
虚拟页偏移 如果这些位
are identical
相同
okay so now you should you should
好了，现在 你 应该知道，你应该
convince yourself that this is true
说服自己，这是 真的
right the the the offset in a virtual
右在虚拟的所述偏移
block is going to be the same as the
块将是一样的
offset in a physical block they're the
在物理块偏移他们是
same size blocks and and you can also
同样大小的块，而你也可以
see why this virtual page number it
为什么这个虚拟页面数它
identifies the the page number in the in
标识中的页码
the page table so imagine so imagine a
页表，以便想象的那么想象
virtual address that's all zeros okay
这样 行不行 是全零的虚拟地址
all zeros so it's virtual address zero
全零所以它的虚拟地址零
and now that that will have a virtual
而现在， 这将有一个虚拟
page number of zero and the byte at that
零页号 ，并 在该字节
address will be it offset zero
地址都会被它抵消为零
okay now increment by one virtual
现在没事了一个虚拟递增
address one so that will be in an offset
解决一个，这样 ，将在偏移
of 1 and it will be in the same virtual
1，这将 是在相同的虚拟
page of zero right now keep incrementing
零页， 现在不断递增
until all of the all of the bits in the
直到所有的 的所有 位 的
virtual page offset are ones and the
虚拟页偏移量是那些与
virtual page numbers is zero okay so
虚拟页码为零 好 了，
this is the last byte in in that virtual
这是在虚拟的最后一个字节
page zero now increment one more time
零页现在增加一个更多的时间
the one bit carries over to the virtual
该一个比特延续到所述虚拟
page number so now now we go to the next
页码所以现在 ，现在我们进入下一个
virtual page and it's at an offset of
虚拟页面，它是在一个偏移
zero okay so so can you see it's sort of
零好吧，所以你能看到它的排序
sort of obvious when you think about it
那种明显，当你想想看
like that you know why we can just take
就像你知道为什么我们可以只取
these these bits after the virtual page
虚拟页面后这些这些位
offset and use them to uniquely identify
偏移，并利用它们 来唯一标识
what virtual page were we're working
什么虚拟页面中我们一直在努力
with okay so let's see how let's see how
用好了，让我们看看如何让我们看看如何
it works in this system in more detail
它工作在本系统中 更详细
so our system our CPU sends a virtual
所以我们的系统中我们的CPU发送一个虚拟
address to the n menu as a result of
地址到n菜单的结果
executing a move instruction or call or
执行移动 指令或致电或
return or any kind of control transfer
返回或任何形式的控制转移
the MMU
该MMU
looks up the the Pte so it fetches the
中查找的私人所以它 的 获取
Pte from the page table stored in
私人从存储在页表
memory so this is actually going off the
内存中，因此这实际上会 关闭
chip on to memory into this Pte stored
芯片上存储器到该私人存储
in memory it gets the it fetches the Pte
在内存中获取它取 的私人
extracts the and uses that tte to
提取并使用该 TTE来
construct the physical address okay and
构建物理地址和好
then it it sense that physical address
那么它 感应到物理地址
to the cache and memory system which
到高速缓冲存储器和系统，其
eventually results in the data being
最终结果，数据会被
returned back to the CPU okay so even
返回到CPU 好了 ，所以即使
for a hit
一击
we still have memory references right
我们仍然有内存引用权
because we have to fetch that that page
因为我们必须获取该该页
table entry now miss is in this parlance
表条目现在怀念的是在这个说法
is called the page fault so in this case
被称为在这种情况下，页面错误等等
the same thing happens as before that
同样的事情发生，因为在此之前，
the CTU sends the virtual address to the
的CTU发送虚拟地址到
MMU
MMU
the MMU fetches that the tte for memory
MMU的获取，对于内存的TTE
but then when it looks then when the MMU
但是当 它看起来那么MMU时
looks at the tte it sees that there's
看着它看到还有的 TTE
either an invalid valid bit or a zero
一个无效的有效位或 零
valid bit or the the it's indicated that
有效位，或者它表明了
the data is stored on disk and so in
数据被存储在磁盘上，因此在
that case it's the MMU triggers a page
它的MMU 这种情况下， 触发页面
fault exception which transfers control
故障异常将控制转移
to this page fault handler to handle or
此页面错误处理程序来处理或
identifies a victim and if it's been
标识一个牺牲品，并且如果它已经
modified copies it out to disk then it
修改其复制到磁盘上 ，然后它
fetches the new page from disk into into
从磁盘 获取 新的页面进入到
memory and up through the cache
内存和多达通过高速缓存
hierarchy okay and then it and then it
层次好，然后，然后将其
causes that the then the handler returns
引起了那么处理程序返回
to the to the process and when I when a
到到过程， 当我 当
handler for a fault returns it causes
处理程序故障返回它 会导致
the the faulting instruction to re
该错误指令重新
execute so now the the move instruction
执行所以现在 的移动 指令
that that faulted is reacts Acutes but
即该故障是 发生反应Acutes但
this time there's a page hit
这时候有一个页面命中
now you may you may be interested how
现在您可以您可能会感兴趣如何
how the cash is integrated into all of
现金是如何集成到所有的
this
这个
so the MMU sent such as page table
所以MMU 发出诸如页表
entries so it passes page table
项，以便它通过页表
addresses to the cash
地址现金
if those myths those go to memory the
如果这些神话的去 记忆
the memory returns those page table
内存返回这些页表
entries to the cache and then ultimately
条目缓存，然后最终
to the to the MMU
到到MMU
the MMU constructs that physical address
该MMU构造一个物理地址
and then its sense that physical address
然后它的感觉， 物理地址
to the cache right so so with caching
到缓存 正确的那么那么与高速缓存
the way we've been caching is done using
我们一直在高速缓存方法是使用完成
physical addresses okay in this case
在这种情况下还行物理地址
it's also possible to construct caches
它也可以构建高速缓存
that work with virtual addresses but yep
与虚拟地址，但没错的工作
yeah so it will get into that okay so
是啊所以它会进入该 好了，所以
the question is how is how is the
问题是如何如何是
virtual address space implemented on
虚拟地址空间中实现的
disk and it what it actually does a much
磁盘，并将其 它实际上 做了很多
more efficient thing than the sort of
比之类的更有效的事情
the abstract model that I described
我所描述的抽象模型
so most pages there's an option when you
所以大多数的网页有，当你的选项
allocate a new virtual memory page you
您分配一个新的 虚拟内存页面
can allocate it so that it's all zeros
所以，这一切都可以零它分配
okay so there's a special you can say I
好 了，有一个特殊的 ，你可以说我
want this I want to allocate a page of
希望此我想分配 的页面
all zeros in that case you know that
在这种情况下，全部为零你知道
page doesn't need to ever get stored on
页面并不需要永远得到存储在
disk right it's just the memory it's as
盘右它只是 它的内存
though it was created on disk and then
虽然它在磁盘上， 然后 创建
loaded into memory so those pages that
加载到内存中，因此这些网页 是
are all zeros don't don't exist on disk
全零，没有 在磁盘上不存在
you know when pages are modified it's a
你知道当网页被修改这是一个
little more pages can be mapped to
多一点的页面可以映射到
particular files for example when we
例如特定的文件时，我们
load an elf binary the pages that
加载ELF程序的页面是
correspond to the code are actually
对应于代码实际上是
mapped to the to the bytes in the binary
映射到于二进制的字节数
that contained the code so that when you
包含的代码 ， 这样， 当你
miss on that page it said it brings in
错过页面上它说，它带来的
those code pages okay so some pages can
这些代码页好了，所以某些页面可能
be mapped to user level files on disk or
被映射 到用户级别的磁盘上的文件或
not they can be anonymous and not mapped
不是他们可以是匿名 和无法映射
so if if they're mapped to user level if
所以，如果如果他们映射到用户级别，如果
they're mapped to user level files and
他们映射到用户级别的文件和
you write to a page then it'll get
你写一个页，然后它会得到
written back to that to the page that
写回到那个页面 是
it's mapped to if it's not mapped to any
它映射到如果它不映射到任何
page it's stored in this area called the
它存储在这个区域页叫
swap area or the swap file okay yes
交换区域或交换文件是没关系
oh yeah so the question is when you load
哦，是这样的问题是，当你加载
a page from disk into memory does it
从磁盘页面到内存做它
also get cached in the cache memory
也得到缓存在高速缓存存储器
hierarchy and the answer is yes so if
层次结构， 答案是肯定的，所以如果
you load an entire page that page will
您加载整个页面，页面会
be broken up into blocks 64 byte blocks
被分解 成块64字节的数据块
and and and loaded into the cache
和和和 加载到缓存中
so everything everything everything that
所以一切的一切的一切，
you fetch from the cache goes through
您将获取从 缓存经过
the from the memory goes through the
从该内存穿过
cache the cache hierarchy okay so I
缓存缓存层次结构好了，所以我
claim that virtual memory works because
声称， 虚拟内存，因为工作
of locality and that's true but if we
局部性的，这就是真实的，但如果我们
still had to fetch if every time we had
仍然有获取如果每次我们有时间
a Miss we still had to go to memory it
一个小姐，我们还是不得不去记忆它
would be too inefficient okay so the the
未免太低效好这样 的
MMU
MMU
speeds up this translation process by
加速了 这一转换过程
caching page table entries in a in a
在一个高速缓存页表项
hardware cache within the MMU called the
在MMU内的硬件缓存，称为
translation lookaside buffer or TLB so
转换后备缓冲器或TLB所以
the TLB is a hardware cache that caches
该TLB是硬件缓存缓存
pges page table entries and it contains
PGES 页表项，它包含
like it contains a cache of the most
喜欢它包含了最高速缓存
recently you know it's just like any
最近你知道这就像 任何
other cache so it contains a cache of
其他缓存使其包含的高速缓存
the most recently used page table
最近 使用 的 页表
entries and so the the mmm you remember
条目， 所以你还记得MMM
the unique part of a virtual address
虚拟地址的独特之处
that defines a virtual page is the
限定了虚拟页是
virtual page number bits okay so the the
虚页号位好，因此在
the TLD uses the VPN portion of the
该TLD使用 的 该VPN 部
virtual address two to two accesses and
虚拟地址两年到两年 访问和
so that just like any other set it has a
使 就像 任何其他的组有一个
set index a set of set index bits which
设置索引的一组集合索引比特，其
are just determined by how many how many
只是被多少来确定多少
entries that are how many sets the TLB
这是多少 设置TLB项
has and it has a tag with four the
有，它有四个标签
remaining bits to disambiguate any
剩余位的歧义的任何
and to disambiguate any cash lines or
并消除歧义任何现金或行
PT's that map to the same set okay so
PT的映射到同一 组好了，
the VPN or the TLB I TLB index maps to
在VPN或TLB 我TLB 指数映射到
this particular set and then and then it
这个特殊的设置，然后， 然后
uses the the TLB used as the TLB glbt
使用所述 TLB 用作TLB同志
bits to disambiguate and determine if
位的歧义，并确定是否
the tte that it's looking for is it is
它在寻找的TTE是它
really stored in the cache okay so the
真正存储在缓存还好使
way this works is CPU generates a
此方法的工作原理是CPU生成
virtual address it goes through the MMU
它通过MMU的 虚拟地址
the MMU instead of looking in memory
MMU的，而不是在寻找记忆
directly going to the page table entry
直接到页表项
it first asked the TLB if it has that it
它首先要求TLB，如果有，它
sends it the VPN and so do you have this
把它的 VPN等你有这
virtual page the P key for this virtual
虚拟页面此虚拟P键
page and if it does the TLB returns a
页面，如果它的TLB返回
hit and it returns that page table entry
打它返回的页表项
which the MMU can then use to construct
该MMU 然后可以用来构造
the physical address to send to the the
物理地址发送给 该
cache and memory system eventually I
高速缓存和内存系统最终我
result in that the data being sent back
导致该数据被发送回
now when you have a Miss then there's
现在，当你有一个小姐则有
this one the MMU checks with the TLB for
这一个MMU与TLB检查
the Pte admit this so then the MMU has
在私人承认这一点所以那么 有 MMU
to go to memory just like before okay so
去记忆像以前一样 好 了，
this is and then everything is the same
这是一切然后是一样的
the memory returns to the PT e to the
内存返回到PT e将
MMU which stashes it in the TLB and just
MMU 其藏匿它在TLB 和公正
like before if there's if there's no
就像如果有前如果没有
room in the if yeah if a PT e has been
房间中如果 如果PT戊己 耶
modified then it has to be written back
修改那么它必须被写 回
out okay just just like any other cache
出好只是像任何其他高速缓存
and eventually the MMU uses that to
并最终MMU使用它来
construct a physical address and then
构造一个物理地址，然后
the data gets sent back
该数据被发送回
okay if you've been paying attention
好吧，如果你一直在关注
unlike a couple people if you've been
不像一对夫妇的人，如果你去过
paying attention you're going to be very
注意你会很
concerned about the size of these page
关注这些页面的 大小
tables right that I mean we've got 4
我的意思是我们已经得到了4桌权
Kbytes suppose we have 4 k bi pages and
字节假设我们有4k的双页，
our effective address space is 48 bits
我们的有效地址空间为48位
like it is with an x86 64 system then
像它是 具有86 64系统然后
and we have an 8x8 byte page table entry
我们有一个8×8字节的页表项
we'd need a page table 512 gigabytes
我们需要一个页表512千兆字节
okay two to the address space two to the
还好 两到 地址空间中的两个给
48 bytes divided by 2 to the 12th bytes
48个字节除以2到 第 12字节
per page okay so that's the number of
每没关系 使页面的数量
page table entries that we need and then
我们需要再页表项
the size of each page table entry is 8
每个页表项的大小为8
bytes so we need almost a terabyte of of
字节，因此，我们需要的几乎万亿字节
DRAM just to hold the page table right
DRAM只是为了保存页面右表
so so then obviously it's not going to
那么那么那么显然它不会
work and it's obviously not how their
工作，这显然 不是他们如何
page tables are really implemented so
页表真正落实等等
the solution is to to use a hierarchy of
解决的办法是使用的层次
page tables so in it so we if we have a
页表所以，所以我们如果我们有一个
two level page table the there's a top
二级页表中有一个顶
of first level page table called the
第一级页表的叫
level one table which is always in
一级表，它总是在
memory it's never never page down and
记忆是永远永远向下翻页和
then and then there's a suit a sequence
然后再有一个穿西装的序列
of level two page tables and they're all
的二级页表和他们都
the same size right and the the first
大小相同的权利和第一
level one table points to the beginning
一级表点开始
of the first level suit table so it
第一级套装表 ， 因此它
contains a physical address that points
包含指向一个物理地址
to the base the second level one table
到基极的第二电平一个表
points to the second level two table and
指向第二二级表
so on okay
等等好吗
so if we have this kind of system
所以，如果我们有这种系统
remember most of the virtual address
记得最清楚的虚拟地址
space is unused right so if we have this
空间是未使用 正确的 ，所以如果我们有这样的
kind of system we can we can avoid
样的系统，我们可以，我们能避免
creating many unnecessary page tables
创造了许多不必要的页表
okay so imagine if we have a two level
好 了，想象一下，如果我们有一个两级
hierarchy so let's look at our virtual
层次结构，以便让我们来 看看我们的虚拟
address space in this example and what
在这个例子中，哪些地址空间
I've allocated two K pages for code and
我已经分配给 两个 代码k个页面和
data for this program and then there's
对这一计划的数据，然后有
there's six K unallocated pages and then
有6个K未分配的 页面 ，然后
the stack then there's a page that's
那么栈有一个页面是
allocated for the stack I'm sorry
分配给堆栈 对不起
there's there's a thousand 24 pages
还有的有一千个24 页
allocated for the stack most of which
分配给栈的最
are I'm sorry there's a region of memory
是我对不起有记忆的区域
that that's the size of a thousand 24
那这是一个千 24 的尺寸
pages but most of them are unallocated
网页，但其中大部分都是未分配
and I've only allocated one for the top
而我只 分配一个顶部
of this for the top of the stack okay so
本作 的堆栈的 顶部 好吧，
given this layout for my my process I
鉴于此布局为我的我的过程中，我
only only need three level two page
只只需要三级 第二页
tables okay the first the first page
表好吗第一的 第一 页
table covers this region of my code and
表涵盖了我的代码本地区和
data the first thousand 24 pages the
数据第一千24页
next page table covers the remaining
下页表涵盖剩余
thousand 24 pages okay so these two
千24页好了，所以这两个
these two level two page tables cover
这两个二级页表覆盖
all of the code and data okay and
所有的代码和数据好和
similarly the what I need for my stack I
同样，我需要为我的堆栈我
just need one page table and it only has
只需要一个页面表，它只有
one one valid Pte
一个一个有效的私人
so at the very last one okay and then I
所以 在最后一个行不行，然后 我
have a single level one table that
有一个级别一个表
points to the three level two tables
指向三级两个表
okay so I with with four page tables
好了 ，所以 我有四个表
I've covered the entire virtual address
我已经覆盖了整个虚拟地址
space now
现在空间
the way that the way that the MMU uses
该方式使MMU使用方式
these multiple page tables to do address
这些多页表做地址
translation is as follows we again we
翻译是再下面我们我们
have a virtual page offset which
还有一个虚拟的页面偏移量
consists of the first P disk and then
由第一P磁盘中，然后
the VPN the remaining bits is the VPN
的VPN中的剩余位是 VPN
for a K level page table are broken up
对于A K级页表被分解
into K sub dpns and each each is the
成K个子 DPNS，并且每个 各自是
same size and so now in this system the
在这个系统中相同的大小，所以现在
upper VPN one which consists of the
上VPN一个其中包括的
uppermost bits of the VPN aren't offset
该VPN的最高位不偏置
into the the level 1 table which is as
成 1 级 表 ，该 表 是作为
before is pointed to by the page table
之前由 页表 指出，
base register okay so the PvP 1 is the
基址寄存器没关系 所以 PVP中 1是
index into the level 1 page table
指数为 1 级页表
remember the level 1 page table points
记得 1级页表点
to the address of the level 2 but our an
到2级，但 我们的地址
entry a PT e in the level 1 table points
在1级表分项中的PTê
to the address of some level 2 page
一些 2 级 页面 的地址
table or it contains the address of some
表或它包含的 一些地址
level 2 page table so that points to the
2级页表，以便指向
base of this level 2 page table and then
这 2级页表的基极，然后
the VPN 2 bits are used as an index into
的VPN 使用 2比特 作为一个指数 到
that level 2 table right and so on
该2级右表等
ok so eventually you get at the a PT e
确定，所以最终你得到的一个PTê
and the level K minus 1 table points to
和等级k减1个分
the beginning of the level K page table
在k级页表的开始
and DP n K points to an offset within
和DPÑK个点到一个内的偏移
that table which finally contains the
该表并最终包含
physical address of the page that we
页面的物理地址，我们
want to access okay and then that
要 访问 行不行，然后说
physical address is used to form the the
物理地址被用于形成所述
PP n portion of the physical address and
的物理地址的PP N部分 和
just like before the virtual page offset
就像虚拟页偏移前
is just copied directly I'm changed to
只是直接复制我改变
the physical page offset
物理页偏移
so is that clear to everybody yes
所以是清楚大家是
question let's see is it always a power
问题让我们看到的是它总是一个电源
of two yes and it's defined by the the
2个是的，它的被定义
architecture so for Intel it's a four
体系结构，以便为英特尔是四
level system now why would it be and
级系统现在为什么它会是和
then the quick could it will it always
那么快能它将它总是
be less than six
少于 六位
I'll give the 64-bit system yeah yeah
我给了 64位系统，是啊是啊
there's only the the block size is fixed
这里只有块大小 是固定的
right so that there's 12 bits here - to
右 使 这里 有 12位 -到
the twelfth is 4k so the remaining is
第十二为 4k所以剩下的 就是
that you actually have 48 bits to play
你实际 有48位玩
with so the remaining 48 bits could
与这样其余48个比特所能
that's right so if it was four if it was
这是正确的，所以如果它是四，如果它是
eight it would be six so you're right
个IT将是6， 所以你说得对
in this scheme it could be at most six
在该方案也可能是在最多六个
turns out in practices it's set it for
原来在它的设置它的做法
and there's a question over here
并有 在 这里 的一个问题
have it like this multi-level system oh
有像这样多层次的系统哦
okay so the question is yeah question is
好 了，问题是呀问题
how does it save you space so recent
它是如何为您节省空间 ，因此 近期
saves you space is you go back to this
为您节省空间， 是你回到这个
other figure maybe I didn't explain this
其他人物也许我没有解释这
well enough
足够好
so you see this if we okay so let's say
所以你看这个，如果我们好了，所以我们说
we wanted to map this virtual address
我们希望这个映射虚拟 地址
space with a single page table we would
用我们将单页表空间
need a PT e for every page within that
需要PT E 对于内的每一页
address whether it was used or not okay
解决这一问题是否被使用或不好吗
it goes back if we had a 48-bit address
它可以追溯到如果我们有一个 48位 地址
space we need enough we need a page
空间，我们需要足够的，我们 需要一个页面
table entry for each each page virtual
每个每一页的虚拟 表项
page in that address space
在地址空间页
okay whether that page was used or not
是否使用或不好吧该页
so let me think about it to to xlviii is
所以 让 我想想 对XLVIII是
a X several several exabytes we need a
一个X数数艾字节，我们需要一个
page table that would had an entry for
这 将 有一个条目页表
each virtual page in that to the 48 bit
每个虚拟页在给48位
address space and most of those pages by
地址空间和大多数这些页面的
far the vast majority would never ever
到目前为止， 绝大多数会永远
be used okay so that's where the waste
使用好了，这就是浪费
comes in okay so here with a multi-level
进来好了，所以这里有一个多层次
page system with this multi-level scheme
页面系统，这种多层次方案
you only need to generate in this case
你只需要在这种情况下产生
these level two if it's a two-level
这些二级如果它是一个两级
system you only need to generate level
系统只需要产生水平
two page tables enough level two pages
第二页表，有两个够级页
to cover the portion of the virtual
以覆盖虚拟 的部分
address space that you're actually using
你实际上正在使用地址空间
okay and that portion of the virtual
好和 虚拟 的 那部分
address space that you're not using at
那你不使用地址空间
this gap right here there's there's no
这种差距就在这里有没有
need to have a page table is that clear
需要有一个页 表是明确
that that's a really good important
那这是一个非常 好的重要
question but you look unconvinced well
的问题，但你看不服气好
yeah yeah you still need you still need
是啊是啊，你还是需要你仍然需要
a page table that has let's see in this
具有页表，让我们在 这 看
case there's 4k byte pages for byte TTE
万一有对字节TTE 4K字节的页
so there's one K you have 1k pges
所以有一个K你有1K PGES
in this so you still need you still need
在此，所以你仍然需要你仍然需要
a level one page table that has 1k pges
有 1K PGES一个一级页表
but those are only eight bytes right I
但这些只有 8个字节的权利 我
mean so you still need to you still need
这样意味着你仍然需要你仍然需要
to have space because you don't know you
有空间，因为你不知道你
know you're not sure which of these
知道你不知道 其中哪些
which reason of the address space you're
其中原因，您的地址空间
going to need to cover okay and it's the
将 需要覆盖很好，而且它的
same thing for here in this case in
在 这种情况下，在 这里同样的事情
these first two PT these first two level
前两个PT前两个级别
two page tables they're their portion of
两页的表格 ，他们是他们的一部分
the address space was actually all being
地址 空间实际上 全部为
used right so each one of these pges at
用于右所以 在这些PGES中的 每一个
level two had to be alec it had to be
二级必须是 亚历克它必须是
initialized and used
初始化和使用
right but in this in this portion of the
右但在此在 的 这 部分
address space to contain the stack this
地址空间 包含堆栈 这
third this third level to page table has
第三第三级 页表有
most most of its pts or no you still
最大多数的患者中有或没有你仍然
have to allocate space for them but
必须 为它们 分配空间 ，但
they're there no okay that's a really
他们有没有 好吧，这是一个 真正的
good question it's important that I hope
很好的问题，重要的是我希望
that's clear any other questions will we
这是明确的其他任何问题，我们将
go on sorry
去对不起
oh okay question we just looked at part
哦，还好问题，我们只是看着一部分
of the exercise exactly just just like
演习 的 确切 才刚刚喜欢
here the MMU remembers doing all of this
这里的MMU 记得做这一切
this is all hardware logic so it and and
这是所有的硬件逻辑，所以它和和
the art the page tables levels is
艺术的 页表层次是
defined by the architecture okay so the
通过该架构还行，以便限定
MMU
MMU
takes the virtual address that's
采取这就是虚拟地址
presented to it and it it uses a portion
呈现给它，它它 使用的部分
a subset of those bits to access each
这些比特的一个子集来访问每个
each page table okay so it's just like
每个页表好了，它就像
did I answer your question okay so it's
为什么我回答你的问题 好了，所以它的
just like the fourth at the level K VPN
就像在第四位等级k VPN
K is used to compute an index into the
K被用于计算一个指数到
level K page - yes
k级页面-是的
in fees range okay the question is why
在费用范围 还好，问题是为什么
are the indices arranged right-to-left
布置在右侧的索引到左
on which diagram oh these are the bits
在其图 哦 这些是位
this is the least significant bit it's
这是最显著位是
always bit zero yeah that's a good
总是零位是啊，这是一个很好的
question so the question was why did
这样 的问题 ，问题是为啥
these in this diagram why are these
这本图中为什么这些
these bits labeled right to left
这些位标记从右到左
starting at zero and the answer is that
从零开始 ，答案是 ，
we're indicating the dick position so
我们指示家伙位置，
zeros the least significant tip and n
归零的至少显著尖端和n
minus one is the most significant bit
减去一个是最显著 位
yes question
是问题
yeah so the question is what's the
是啊所以这个问题是有什么
overhead involved in these when you have
开销参与这些，当你有
these multiple levels now are you
这些多层次的 ，现在是你
talking about overhead - yeah well so
谈到开销 - 是这么好
there's clearly if you don't get TLB
有清楚的，如果你没有得到TLB
hits it would be a lot of overhead
命中这将是一个很大的开销
because it would be you would be
因为这将是你会
fetching pges from multiple page tables
从多个页表取PGES
for memory so that but because of
对于内存中， 以便但 由于
locality the chances are almost that the
当地的几率几乎是，
chances this level one table covers the
机会这个级别一个表涵盖
entire address space so it's always
整个地址空间，所以它总是
going to be in the PG in the TLB these
将要 在 PG在 这些 TLB
the level these these these level two
水平这些这些这些二级
tables are covering a huge swath of the
表覆盖的巨大的大片
address space so chances are they're
地址空间，所以很有可能他们 是
going to be in the TLB - right so so as
要 在TLB中-右使，从而
long as your program has reasonable
只要你的程序有合理
locality most of the most of these most
当地大部分的大多数这些最
of these lookups are going to hit in the
这些查找的是要在打
TLB okay so it turns out that the
TLB 好了， 事实 证明 ，在
overhead with reasonably written
开销合理的书面
programs is is it's negligible
程序是是可忽略不计
and but that's a very it's a very
并且但这是一个非常这是一个非常
important consideration and you know
你知道重要的考虑因素
maybe that maybe that speaks against
也许 ，也许这 对说话
increasing at some point if you had too
在某些时候增加，如果你有太多
many page tables you might you might
许多页表你可能你 可能
increase the probability of misses in
增加未命中的概率
the TLB so it's probably something they
在TLB 因此它可能是他们的东西
very carefully considered okay any other
非常仔细地考虑 好了其他任何
questions yeah yeah we use sedimentation
问题是 啊 是 啊，我们用沉淀
flood paging so he is the identification
洪水分页所以 他的身份
label recommended Lina against Ward
标签 建议丽娜对 沃德
Realty budget homeboy the question was
物业预算巨蟹座的问题是
how does segmentation fit into this and
如何做分割适应这个和
we're not going to go there so in in
我们不会去那里所以在
earlier Intel systems such as the
早期的Intel系统如
actually the first Intel system I
实际上是第一个英特尔系统I
program it was a 286 in the 286 know is
程序是 在286 286 知道是
neat it was the 8086 anyway earlier in
整齐它是8086 反正前面
earlier Intel systems had 16-bit
早期的Intel系统有16位
addresses which is tiny right it's only
地址是 正确的 微小 这只是
2 to the 16th for your address space and
2至16 为您的地址空间，
so as a hack to try to increase the
所以作为一个黑客，试图增加
effective size of the of this address
的这个地址的有效尺寸
space to introduce the notion of
空间引入的概念
segmentation and so there were four
分割等有四个
segments 4-bit there was a register
段的4位 有一个寄存器
segment registers that contain four four
包含四四段寄存器
bits that could be applied to the
可能被应用到所述位
address so an address was the the
地址，一个地址是的
combination of the segment knows more
该 段 的组合 更知道
than
比
yeah you need the segment formed the
是的，你需要的段形成的
address gun was a combination of the
地址枪是的组合
segment bits plus the address so you
段位加上地址，以便您
could use the segment bits to create an
可以用段位来创建
offset so it was a - it was it
偏移于是就出现了-这是它
effectively a - to the 20/20 bit address
实际上是- 20/20 位地址
space but you can only address you can
空间，但你只能地址 ，您可以
only access it in 2 to the 16th chunks
只访问它在2到16块
right so the segment would would
权利，使该段会会
determine an offset into into the sum
确定的偏移量到的总和
and offset into the that this 20-bit
和偏移量，这20位
address space and then from that you can
地址空间，然后从 ， 你可以
address 16 bits so it was this very
解决 16 位 所以这是这个非常
unsatisfying devilishly hard to program
不满意过分地硬编程
thing because you can only access 16 bit
的事情，因为你只能访问16位
chunks at a time so anyway we're not
在一个时间块所以无论如何 我们 不
going to a few years later they came to
打算几年后，他们 来到了
their senses and just created a real
他们的感觉和刚刚创建一个真正的
virtual memory system with with linear
虚拟存储器系统与线性
drill spaces but you know really there
钻空间，但你知道真的存在
yeah I don't know we're just I'm not
是啊，我不知道，我们只是我不
even sure if if they do address
即使知道如果他们这样做地址
translation on those actually so I'm not
翻译对那些实际，所以我不
sure but you really don't want to go
知道，但你真的 不想去
there yeah
有啊
oh it does it does so the question is it
哦，它确实它这样做的问题是，
doesn't exist anymore
不存在 了
everything Intel's been incredibly good
一切英特尔一直非常的好
about maintaining backward compatibility
关于保持向后兼容性
so that stuff's all in there but there's
所以这些东西的都在那里 ，但有
a mode that when you when you boot your
的模式， 当你启动你 的 时候
system up you set a bit that says I want
系统使用你所设置了一下，说我想
a linear address space okay any other
一个线性地址空间行的任何 其它
question
题
oh no VT m2 is the offset okay so the
哦，不VT m2的 偏移还好使
question is why do we care about VPN -
问题是，我们为什么要 关心VPN -
since that it points to the level two
因为它指向二级
table so what what what gives you the
表，什么什么什么给你
beginning of the level two table is the
一开始的水平两个表是
Pte entry in the level 1 table okay so
在1级 表 私人入口 好了，
the the level 1 table points to the
所述1级表指向
beginning of that level to pay table and
开始该级别的支付表
VPN - gives you the offset into that
VPN -让你的偏移成
that level 2 table
该2级表
so these it finds the address by taking
所以这些是通过采取查找地址
the the base address and then DPN 2
的基地址，然后DPN 2
times the PT II sighs okay good good any
倍PT II 叹息 一般好 良好的任何
other questions
其他问题
okay well that'll do it for today next
好清楚，会 为今天做 下一个
week or on Thursday we'll look at how
一周周四，我们将看看如何
virtual memory is implemented in real
虚拟内存在实际执行
systems say and in Linux
系统 说，而在Linux